<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on LoopedNetwork</title>
    <link>https://looped.network/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on LoopedNetwork</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2023 - LoopedNetwork</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 20:22:04 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://looped.network/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fedora 38 Release</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/fedora-38-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 20:22:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/fedora-38-release/</guid>
      <description>I saw on Mastodon earlier today that Fedora 38 was released. I had checked several weeks ago on when it was expected, and while I knew it was going to be soon, it had fallen off my radar while I&amp;rsquo;ve been preoccupied with a few other things. While I tend to be a bit more cautious with my work machines, on my personal machines I typically pull the trigger on major new OS releases with a fairly cavalier attitude, so as soon as I had a moment I went to get the upgrade rolling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Manjaro Linux Invalid Or Corrupt Package Error</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/manjaro-invalid-corrupt-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 18:30:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/manjaro-invalid-corrupt-package/</guid>
      <description>As the title alludes to, this morning I tried updating my Pinebook Pro running Manjaro Linux through my normal method:
sudo pacman -Syu Today, this resulted in an error message about the libibus package:
warning: could not fully load metadata for package libibus-1.5.26-2 error: failed to prepare transaction (invalid or corrupted package)
Fun. I first wanted to see if it was really just this package that was causing the problem or if there were other issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling GSS-NTLMSSP For Alpine Linux</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/gss-ntlmssp-alpine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 18:23:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/gss-ntlmssp-alpine/</guid>
      <description>I recently found myself working on a project which required the GSS-NTLMSSP library. The application is going to be delivered via Kubernetes, so I needed to build a Docker image with this library. The project&amp;rsquo;s build instructions are pretty clear about what the dependencies are, but given that this was going to be a Docker image, I wanted to use Alpine Linux as the base image in order to keep the image size as small as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
