<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home Office on LoopedNetwork</title>
    <link>https://looped.network/tags/home-office/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home Office on LoopedNetwork</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 19:06:26 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://looped.network/tags/home-office/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Home Office Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/home-office-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 19:06:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/home-office-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>In a move that was highly overdue, I finally redid my home office several weeks ago. It&amp;rsquo;s actually embarrassing to share, but this is what it had looked like prior to the overhaul&amp;hellip; not that I would even call this an office:
Background Saying that the desk is small is an understatement. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually owned this desk for years, and the story behind it is that I needed a small desk at my previous apartment.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;In a move that was &lt;em&gt;highly&lt;/em&gt; overdue, I finally redid my home office several weeks ago. It&amp;rsquo;s actually embarrassing to share, but this is what it had looked like prior to the overhaul&amp;hellip; not that I would even call this an office:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/old_tiny_desk.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Tiny, cramped desk with one monitor, 75% keyboard, and a laptop stand&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saying that the desk is small is an understatement. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually owned this desk for &lt;strong&gt;years&lt;/strong&gt;, and the story behind it is that I needed a small desk at my previous apartment. This was back when I was still gaming regularly (read: spending every waking moment of my life playing &lt;em&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t working.) Rather than clutter up my living room with gaming stuff, I had a decent-sized desk in my bedroom where my gaming setup lived. I started working from home 3 days a week for the job I had at the time, though, so I decided to get a second desk that I would use for that instead of trying to do both at my gaming desk, which really didn&amp;rsquo;t have the room for it considering my gaming desktop was sitting on top of it. As a result, I opted to buy this fairly small desk so that it would still fit in my bedroom alongside all the other furniture without making things feel too cramped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward several years, and I was in the middle of moving for a new job. At this point I had mostly stopped playing games, and I ended up throwing out my gaming desk since it was around 12 years old. It was fairly beat up, it had several dings along the surface that I needed to keep covered with a desk mat, and it was starting to sag in the middle. Since the job I was taking didn&amp;rsquo;t have any remote work (at the time), I decided I was okay with just moving the small desk since I&amp;rsquo;d only be using it occasionally with my personal laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a little more and the COVID19 pandemic changed everything. I started working from home full time. While using such a small desk every day felt a little silly, early on I was under the impression that we&amp;rsquo;d be going back to the office after a few weeks. It was also spring, so I tried to spend time working outside on my deck since I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going anywhere else at the time. Suffice to say, working remotely for just a few months isn&amp;rsquo;t what happened, and I became a fully remote employee. However, I just felt used to the desk and honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t give it much additional thought. This continued for several years until I eventually left that job for my current role, which is also 100% remote. At this point I realized that if I was going to keep living in my current apartment, I really needed to upgrade my setup. After some research convinced me that staying in my current home was the best decision, I knew it was time for my long-overdue upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-upgrade&#34;&gt;The Upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent some time chatting with a good friend of mine who happens to be something of a guru when it comes to all things home computing, and she helped me narrow down some of the different options that would be a good fit. I have a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; of space, as you can probably tell from the first photo, because my &amp;ldquo;home office&amp;rdquo; is actually what is intended to be my dining room. However, I have a bar-top in my apartment with several stools at it, and since I live by myself I literally always eat my meals there; I actually got rid of the table and chairs I used at my last apartment when I moved since I knew I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t use them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main idea was that I wanted to have 2 distinct setups: one for work and one for personal. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t so much for a mental break between the two but just to keep me from having to constantly be swapping peripherals between my laptops. My initial thought was to get a very long desk and have two distinct spaces right next to one another. After looking at a few options in person, though, I decided I liked the idea of two medium-length desks that I could put together in an L shape. That&amp;rsquo;s what I eventually ended up deciding to go with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/new_desk_setup_main.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;2 desks in an L configuration with 2 distinct computer setups&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way back from buying the desks, we also stopped at a computer hardware store where I bought the second (larger) monitor to include with the new setup. This allows me to just operate off of the 2 external displays while I&amp;rsquo;m working, leaving the laptop itself closed. To the right is my current personal setup, which is just a laptop on a stand that brings it close enough for me to use given how terrible my vision is. I &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; eventually get a monitor for this setup as well, but I&amp;rsquo;m also debating getting either a new laptop or swapping to a mini-PC of some sort. Until I make a firm decision on that, I&amp;rsquo;m happy enough with a laptop stand and 2 wireless peripherals I never need to worry about plugging and unplugging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also ended up changing the rest of the space a bit, taking a large chair that I had for years and tucking it into a corner after shifting around a small set of bookshelves and a replacement for the coffee table in the first photo that I swapped with a different one in my apartment to keep the all-black-everything theme going:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/new_desk_setup_lounge.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Different angle of the same office from the last photo showing the edge of the desk and a bucket chair&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes for a cozy little &amp;ldquo;lounge&amp;rdquo; part of my office. I usually sit there in the morning with a cup of coffee and read before I start work for the day. I&amp;rsquo;ll also hop into the chair to &lt;del&gt;doom&lt;/del&gt;scroll through my phone when I&amp;rsquo;m taking a break or if I&amp;rsquo;m on a call that doesn&amp;rsquo;t require me to be in front of my computer. In fact, if I&amp;rsquo;m not actively working on my computer as a part of the call, I actually like stepping away from it to ensure that I focus on the call instead of getting distracted by some code I was in the middle of working on, a Slack message, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I feel a little ridiculous for working under such cramped conditions for so long, it really was something I just got acclimated to and didn&amp;rsquo;t feel particularly inconvenienced by at the time. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded, though, this is easily my favorite part of the apartment, and I find myself spending a lot of time here even when I&amp;rsquo;m not working. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how much easier it is to focus on things like my personal side projects or maintaining this blog when I have a comfortable space to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
