<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on LoopedNetwork</title>
    <link>https://looped.network/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on LoopedNetwork</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2023 - LoopedNetwork</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 19:06:29 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://looped.network/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ice Cubes Mastodon Client</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/icecubes-mastodon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 19:06:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/icecubes-mastodon/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve used Mastodon off-and-on for around 5 or 6 years at this point. I&amp;rsquo;ve bounced around a handful of servers, and for a (relatively brief) period I even ran my own instance. My frequent comings and goings from Mastodon speak much more to my fleeting interest with social media than with any problems with the platform. While no software is perfect, I think Mastodon does a terrific job of what it sets out to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora 38 Release</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/fedora-38-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 20:22:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/fedora-38-release/</guid>
      <description>I saw on Mastodon earlier today that Fedora 38 was released. I had checked several weeks ago on when it was expected, and while I knew it was going to be soon, it had fallen off my radar while I&amp;rsquo;ve been preoccupied with a few other things. While I tend to be a bit more cautious with my work machines, on my personal machines I typically pull the trigger on major new OS releases with a fairly cavalier attitude, so as soon as I had a moment I went to get the upgrade rolling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logitech Ergo K860 Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/logitech_ergo_k860/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 16:01:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/logitech_ergo_k860/</guid>
      <description>Background I recently ran into some issues with the keyboard I had been using for the past few years and decided it was time to opt for something new. The keyboard I was moving away from was the Keychron K2 V2. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a love-hate relationship with mechanical keyboards, flipping between feeling like they give me a really good typing experience and thinking they sacrifice too much in terms of ergonomics to be worth the price of admission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pylint Import Error</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/pylint-import-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 15:57:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/pylint-import-error/</guid>
      <description>I recently found myself quickly checking in on a Python project outside of my normal Neovim workflow. I was basically just trying to quickly re-familiarize myself with some code that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t looked at or thought about in a few months before deploying it for a customer. If I&amp;rsquo;m feeling particularly lazy when doing something like this, I&amp;rsquo;ll often open something up in Sublime rather than Neovim just because it allows me to quickly scroll through a project and hop between files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Months With VSCode</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/two-months-vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 18:07:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/two-months-vscode/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve written about before, Vim (specifically Neovim) is my editor of choice. I use it with Python, Go, Groovy, and to write these posts in Markdown. I find Vim&amp;rsquo;s modal setup to be the most efficient way to edit text, and after becoming (moderately) proficient with the motions I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m significantly faster than if I had to bother with arrow keys and various combinations of Command, Ctrl, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare Pages Errors With CORS</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/cloudflare-pages-cors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 19:59:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/cloudflare-pages-cors/</guid>
      <description>Shortly after making my post regarding my return to Hugo yesterday, I noticed a potential issue with my new site. While testing it from the local Hugo development server everything looked great. After linking Cloudflare Pages with the repo and deploying it, though, things started to misbehave. Namely, the CSS and JavaScript weren&amp;rsquo;t being loaded, giving me an extremely ugly site with the .svg logo being the full width of the screen, a default white background, and black text with blue links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/back-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 18:12:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/back-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>After a little over a year with Write.as, this site is once again being built with Hugo, my favorite static site generator. I&amp;rsquo;m currently hosting it through Cloudflare Pages. I don&amp;rsquo;t know that Cloudflare is any better or worse than other static hosts out there, but since I already use them for a handful of things (including hosting another site), I figure it&amp;rsquo;s easier for me to just keep everything in one place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Music Classical</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/apple-music-classical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 19:11:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/apple-music-classical/</guid>
      <description>Last week Apple released Apple Music Classical, a variant of their Apple Music streaming service (and which operates off of the same subscription) but that only contains classical music. While I&amp;rsquo;m no expert by any stretch, I&amp;rsquo;m actually a bit of a classical music fan. It&amp;rsquo;s something I turn to frequently when I want music without any lyrics (e.g. when I&amp;rsquo;m reading or trying to focus on something for work.) My car&amp;rsquo;s stereo is even always tuned to the local classical music station, though I typically only listen to it for a few moments until Bluetooth connects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Design Update</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/site-design-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 19:09:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/site-design-update/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post is no longer accurate since the site has moved from Write.as. However, here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot of what it looked like at the time; I was quite happy with it!
The entire time this particular site has been in existence at Write.as, I&amp;rsquo;ve used the Carbontwelve theme for it. It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly slick theme with some nice effects; I&amp;rsquo;ve been fairly happy with it. My only real issue is that it&amp;rsquo;s a light theme, which I (more or less) never use for anything given the option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Office Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/home-office-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 19:06:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/home-office-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>In a move that was highly overdue, I finally redid my home office several weeks ago. It&amp;rsquo;s actually embarrassing to share, but this is what it had looked like prior to the overhaul&amp;hellip; not that I would even call this an office:
Background Saying that the desk is small is an understatement. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually owned this desk for years, and the story behind it is that I needed a small desk at my previous apartment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Want Functional Scrollbars</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/functional-scrollbars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 19:02:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/functional-scrollbars/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been lamenting the death of the functional scrollbar. Remember back in the day when scrollbars looked like this?
The scrollbars were prominent because they were meant to be used. You were expected to grab one with your mouse and move it up and down. Today, scrollbars have a much different appearance and expectation of functionality. This is what they look like in Firefox on Gnome 43 running under Fedora 37:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying T-Mobile Home Internet</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/tmobile-home-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 18:58:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/tmobile-home-internet/</guid>
      <description>For the majority of my life, I&amp;rsquo;ve only had one Internet service provider where I lived. That was originally just a single dial-up provider when I was growing up to only having one coaxial cable provider at 4 different apartments in the span of 11 years. That recently changed when I went from having a single provider (coax) where I&amp;rsquo;m currently at to having 3 providers (coax, 5G, and fiber.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proton and SimpleLogin</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/proton-simplelogin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 18:57:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/proton-simplelogin/</guid>
      <description>While going down a rabbit hole on Mastodon the other day, I stumbled across a post from SimpleLogin saying that they were now a part of the Proton family. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of ProtonMail for a long time, and now also use both Proton Drive and Proton Calendar regularly (especially now that they have iOS apps.) While I&amp;rsquo;ve not used a lot of email alias services like this before, I have used the one Apple offers through iCloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decreasing Domains</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/decreasing-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 18:31:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/decreasing-domains/</guid>
      <description>It just dawned on me that I&amp;rsquo;ve finally made good progress in decreasing the number of domains that I own. I&amp;rsquo;ve historically purchased domains on a whim; when I&amp;rsquo;m bored or sitting on a bar stool somewhere, I&amp;rsquo;ll grab my phone and check if random domains that pop into my head are available. While the overwhelming majority of them would be taken, I&amp;rsquo;d occasionally strike upon something that hadn&amp;rsquo;t been snatched up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Manjaro Linux Invalid Or Corrupt Package Error</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/manjaro-invalid-corrupt-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 18:30:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/manjaro-invalid-corrupt-package/</guid>
      <description>As the title alludes to, this morning I tried updating my Pinebook Pro running Manjaro Linux through my normal method:
sudo pacman -Syu Today, this resulted in an error message about the libibus package:
warning: could not fully load metadata for package libibus-1.5.26-2 error: failed to prepare transaction (invalid or corrupted package)
Fun. I first wanted to see if it was really just this package that was causing the problem or if there were other issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting Audio From Video With FFmpeg</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/ffmpeg-audio-from-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 18:28:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/ffmpeg-audio-from-video/</guid>
      <description>Just a few moments ago I needed to extract the audio component out of a video file into some type of standalone audio file, like .mp3. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Audacity to record audio, I figured maybe it had some capability for ripping it out of video.
My initial searches gave me results like this which quickly made it clear that while this is technically possible, it requires some add-ins that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to mess around with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kubectl logs Symbolic Link Error</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/kubectl-symbolic-link-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 18:27:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/kubectl-symbolic-link-error/</guid>
      <description>I recently ran across an interesting error with my development Kubernetes cluster, and while I still have no idea what I may have done to cause it, I at least figured out how to rectify it. As is commonly the case, most of the things I end up deploying to Kubernetes simply log to standard out so that I can view logs with the kubectl logs command. While running this against a particular deployment, though, I received an error:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kinit Fails Only When Using Keytab File</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/kinit-keytab-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 18:26:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/kinit-keytab-fail/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been working through getting WinRM connectivity working between a Linux container and a bunch of Windows servers. I&amp;rsquo;m using the venerable pywinrm library. It works great, but there was a decent bit of setup for the underlying host to make it work that I had been unfamiliar with; you can&amp;rsquo;t just create a client object, plug in some credentials, and go. A big part of this for my setup was configuring krb5 to be able to speak to Active Directory appropriately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Time Error Checking and Code Completion With Neovim</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/neovim-lsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 18:25:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/neovim-lsp/</guid>
      <description>I had written a few months ago on Medium that I was trying to switch from using VS Code as my main editor to Vim. As I mentioned in that post, I&amp;rsquo;ve used Vim for years now, but never as my &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; editor for when I need to get serious work done, such as with my job. I also swapped from vanilla Vim to Neovim, which I found to have a few quality of life improvements that I enjoyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling GSS-NTLMSSP For Alpine Linux</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/gss-ntlmssp-alpine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 18:23:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/gss-ntlmssp-alpine/</guid>
      <description>I recently found myself working on a project which required the GSS-NTLMSSP library. The application is going to be delivered via Kubernetes, so I needed to build a Docker image with this library. The project&amp;rsquo;s build instructions are pretty clear about what the dependencies are, but given that this was going to be a Docker image, I wanted to use Alpine Linux as the base image in order to keep the image size as small as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing Functions, Classes, and Methods From Other PowerShell Files</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/powershell-import-classes-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 18:20:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/powershell-import-classes-functions/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been working on a project that requires me to use PowerShell. I actually feel relatively fluent in PowerShell since it was my main scripting language for a little over a decade while I worked as a sysadmin in highly Windows-centric environments that involved me automating as much of my job as possible in order to be able to do things like sleep on occasion. However, my PowerShell work rarely (read: never) went beyond single file scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Cloud Variables Are All Strings</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/terraform-cloud-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 18:19:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/terraform-cloud-variables/</guid>
      <description>This post easily falls into the “so ridiculous that it shouldn’t be a post” category. However, considering how long I ended up stuck on it earlier today, I figure it’s worth making if it stands a chance of helping even one other person avoid the same fate as me. 😅
I’ve started doing a little bit of work with the Terraform Cloud API. Specifically, I was looking at being able to update a workspace variable through code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
