<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LoopedNetwork</title>
    <link>https://looped.network/</link>
    <description>Recent content on LoopedNetwork</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>LoopedNetwork</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 18:12:18 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://looped.network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 18:16:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer (Python, C#, Groovy) with a background in DevOps (Puppet, K8s, Terraform), networking (FortiNet, Cradlepoint), and systems administration (Active Directory, DNS, DHCP.) I used to blog very regularly for years before giving it up for a while, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how long it lasts this time. In the meantime, you can also find me at:
 GitHub Mastodon Goodreads WakaTime  </description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer (Python, C#, Groovy) with a background in DevOps (Puppet, K8s, Terraform), networking (FortiNet, Cradlepoint), and systems administration (Active Directory, DNS, DHCP.) I used to blog very regularly for years before giving it up for a while, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how long it lasts this time. In the meantime, you can also find me at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jfabry-noc&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.online/@looped_network&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://goodreads.com/loopednetwork&#34;&gt;Goodreads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wakatime.com/@LoopedNetwork&#34;&gt;WakaTime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/back-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 18:12:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/back-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>After a little over a year with Write.as, this site is once again being built with Hugo, my favorite static site generator. I&amp;rsquo;m currently hosting it through Cloudflare Pages. I don&amp;rsquo;t know that Cloudflare is any better or worse than other static hosts out there, but since I already use them for a handful of things (including hosting another site), I figure it&amp;rsquo;s easier for me to just keep everything in one place.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;After a little over a year with &lt;a href=&#34;https://write.as&#34;&gt;Write.as&lt;/a&gt;, this site is once again being built with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, my favorite static site generator. I&amp;rsquo;m currently hosting it through &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.cloudflare.com/&#34;&gt;Cloudflare Pages&lt;/a&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t know that Cloudflare is any better or worse than other static hosts out there, but since I already use them for a handful of things (including hosting another site), I figure it&amp;rsquo;s easier for me to just keep everything in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few reasons for the change, which is probably a bit odd given that I &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://looped.network/posts/site-design-update/&#34;&gt;updated the design&lt;/a&gt;. One is that while Write.as is a &lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt; service&amp;ndash;I honestly have nothing but good things to say about it&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s still a small project run by a single person. What happens to the service if something happens to that person, if that person decides to move on to something else, etc? While it is easy enough to export my data from Write.as, it&amp;rsquo;s still simpler to get it somewhere else while I still have a fairly small number of posts at it; when I started there I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to move most of my &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; old content that I just backed up at &lt;a href=&#34;https://loopednetwork.medium.com/&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason is that, for reasons I&amp;rsquo;ll cover in another post at another time, I&amp;rsquo;m once again circling back to taking stock of all of my various subscriptions. I actually did a &lt;a href=&#34;https://sameshadeofdifference.com/episodes/mo-money-mo-money&#34;&gt;podcast about this exact problem&lt;/a&gt; (back when I was still podcasting.) When subscriptions are relatively cheap, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to just not think about them and how they all add up. In this case, timing is fortuitous as I had &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; received the notice that my Write.as subscription would be renewing; it&amp;rsquo;s due on the 10th. That&amp;rsquo;s $72 that I don&amp;rsquo;t really &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; to spend since I can easily build and host the site for free. Having that done for me was a matter of convenience that may not necessarily be worth the price of admission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came to picking a theme, I stuck with some of the key things I discussed in my post about redoing my Write.as theme. I wanted something dark that would allow me to only show a preview of each post rather than having the full content of every post displayed on each page. While I was tempted to go with the tried-and-trusted Terminal theme that I&amp;rsquo;ve used many times before, this time I decided to try &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/themes/hugo-ficurinia/&#34;&gt;Ficurinia&lt;/a&gt;. The default look is quite nice, though it offers a ton of customization options if I eventually want to tweak it a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only real issue with it is that I the link to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.online/@looped_network&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; account doesn&amp;rsquo;t include the &lt;code&gt;rel=&amp;quot;me&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; part that&amp;rsquo;s required for my site to show up as being verified:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34; data-lang=&#34;html&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;rel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;me&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;https://mastodon.online/@looped_network&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;Mastodon&amp;lt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I may see if I can figure out how to add that to the theme and, if so, open a PR for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Music Classical</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/apple-music-classical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 19:11:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/apple-music-classical/</guid>
      <description>Last week Apple released Apple Music Classical, a variant of their Apple Music streaming service (and which operates off of the same subscription) but that only contains classical music. While I&amp;rsquo;m no expert by any stretch, I&amp;rsquo;m actually a bit of a classical music fan. It&amp;rsquo;s something I turn to frequently when I want music without any lyrics (e.g. when I&amp;rsquo;m reading or trying to focus on something for work.) My car&amp;rsquo;s stereo is even always tuned to the local classical music station, though I typically only listen to it for a few moments until Bluetooth connects.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Last week Apple released &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/music-movie/introducing-apple-music-classical/1671879126&#34;&gt;Apple Music Classical&lt;/a&gt;, a variant of their Apple Music streaming service (and which operates off of the same subscription) but that only contains classical music. While I&amp;rsquo;m no expert by any stretch, I&amp;rsquo;m actually a bit of a classical music fan. It&amp;rsquo;s something I turn to frequently when I want music without any lyrics (e.g. when I&amp;rsquo;m reading or trying to focus on something for work.) My car&amp;rsquo;s stereo is even always tuned to the local classical music station, though I typically only listen to it for a few moments until Bluetooth connects. Despite liking classical music, though, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine why this would be a standalone app. Apple Music already has a great selection of classical and pretty terrific playlists&amp;hellip; wouldn&amp;rsquo;t this just basically be the same thing as what I see in the Classical category?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine claimed to have some insight into the reasoning, though I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s true or not. He told me that he heard on a podcast (I don&amp;rsquo;t recall which one, if he even mentioned it) that people who are &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; into Classical music don&amp;rsquo;t want to bother with seeing anything else. On one hand, I think it seems like a bit of a stretch since, unless there&amp;rsquo;s some sort of niche classical streaming service out there, everyone is already used to using Apple Music, Spotify, Prime Music, etc. On the other hand, I know I got really irritated when services (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you, Spotify) started including podcasts, recommending podcasts, and generally bugging me to listen to garbage that I was absolutely never going to listen to, so I can kind of understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, I had set the app to auto-download so I could check it out whenever it became available. I started poking around as soon as I got the notification that it was ready, and my immediate reaction was that this was, quite clearly, something for the true classical die-hards. I&amp;rsquo;m more of a &amp;ldquo;show me a bunch of playlists and I&amp;rsquo;ll pick from the one that I think looks the best for the current situation&amp;rdquo; person when it comes to classical music, and Apple Music Classical is absolutely not the app for that. In fact, the number of Apple-curated playlists that are surfaced seems to actually be smaller than what I see in full-fledged Apple Music; several of the playlists I commonly come back to weren&amp;rsquo;t even shown in the Classical app (which probably says something about my taste in classical music.) Those playlists were at least still available within the app since they showed up as things I had recently played, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than focus on what Apple curates, the app seems to focus more on making it easy for users to find what &lt;strong&gt;they&lt;/strong&gt; want. It&amp;rsquo;s simple to quickly surface music by both composer and performer. Again, I&amp;rsquo;m not on the level where that&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;m looking for, but I can certainly understand how nice it would be if that&amp;rsquo;s your jam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What really threw me for a loop, though, is that even &lt;strong&gt;shuffling&lt;/strong&gt; didn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be an option. When listening to a new album for the first time, across any genre, I always listen to it in order. After that, however, I&amp;rsquo;m a prodigious user of the shuffle function. Albums, playlists, etc. all get shuffled. Apple Music Classical doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be cool with that. Instead of the two buttons one would normally see in Apple Music for &amp;ldquo;Play&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Shuffle&amp;rdquo;, Apple Music Classical &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; shows &amp;ldquo;Play.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/apple_music_classical1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;A playlist in Apple Music Classical just showing a play button without any shuffle option&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even using the normal UI elements to give the option for shuffling will only include the icon for looping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/apple_music_classical2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Apple Music Classical controls showing loop as the only option&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was a bit of a dealbreaker for me since I most commonly come back to a handful of playlists (which Apple does a good job of updating on the regular) and shuffling through them so I&amp;rsquo;m not always hearing the same handful of songs at the start. The lack shuffle means I&amp;rsquo;m just going to keep listening to the same playlists through the regular Apple Music app instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the whole, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I would say that Apple Music Classical is bad, per se, but I just still fail to see the point of it. If you&amp;rsquo;re already paying for full access to Apple Music, why not just use that? I&amp;rsquo;d think it would be nice to have Apple recommend songs and create weekly playlists for you, which should still be based around classical if that&amp;rsquo;s all someone listens to. (Note: I&amp;rsquo;m 100% not saying that I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo;; this was just my personal impression. If a classical guru out there happens to stumble across this post and loves the Classical app over Apple Music, I&amp;rsquo;d be extremely curious to hear the reasoning!)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Design Update</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/site-design-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 19:09:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/site-design-update/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post is no longer accurate since the site has moved from Write.as. However, here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot of what it looked like at the time; I was quite happy with it!
The entire time this particular site has been in existence at Write.as, I&amp;rsquo;ve used the Carbontwelve theme for it. It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly slick theme with some nice effects; I&amp;rsquo;ve been fairly happy with it. My only real issue is that it&amp;rsquo;s a light theme, which I (more or less) never use for anything given the option.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This post is no longer accurate since the site has moved from Write.as. However, here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot of what it looked like at the time; I was quite happy with it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/writeas_blog_dracula.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of this blog with a Dracula theme&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire time this particular site has been in existence at &lt;a href=&#34;https://write.as/&#34;&gt;Write.as&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://write.as/themes/carbontwelve&#34;&gt;Carbontwelve&lt;/a&gt; theme for it. It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly slick theme with some nice effects; I&amp;rsquo;ve been fairly happy with it. My only real issue is that it&amp;rsquo;s a light theme, which I (more or less) never use for anything given the option. I&amp;rsquo;m not &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt; with CSS and have designed several decent-looking sites, both personally and for work, but it&amp;rsquo;s not something I enjoy. It&amp;rsquo;s more of a frustration I work to overcome and then avoid looking at again for as long as I can. As a result, I typically stick with using designs from others where possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, however, I decided to play around with putting something together to make the design of this site something more in line with me. The nice part about Write.as is that, at least for Pro accounts, you have full control of your CSS, and it all just gets updated in one section of the settings for each blog. This means that it&amp;rsquo;s simple to just copy what you have and save it, which I did as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/jfabry-noc/c7a69d69e2bb9d7031a3a48dc04441aa&#34;&gt;gist&lt;/a&gt;. Then if any changes aren&amp;rsquo;t to my liking, I can just paste back what I originally had. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d do this since I had made a couple of minor tweaks from the default Carbontwelve theme that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have to recreate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My ultimate goal was to design the site with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dracula/dracula-theme&#34;&gt;Dracula theme&lt;/a&gt; colors. I used these previously in a WordPress theme I built, and I loved the way it turned out. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have to start from scratch, though, so I looked through all of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://write.as/themes/&#34;&gt;current themes&lt;/a&gt; to see if there was something that would work as a base for me. I ultimately decided to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://write.as/themes/crop-lee&#34;&gt;Crop Lee&lt;/a&gt;. It was simple enough to work my way through all of the site elements, adjusting the colors as needed. I spent a decent bit of time playing around with the formatting of code blocks so they would really pop, such as in posts like this one on &lt;a href=&#34;https://looped.network/fixing-manjaro-linux-invalid-or-corrupt-package-error&#34;&gt;errors I saw when updating my Manjaro installation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing I was unhappy with was the default view when just landing at &lt;a href=&#34;https://looped.network&#34;&gt;https://looped.network&lt;/a&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t like the default WriteFreely view that shows the full post content in a font that&amp;rsquo;s slightly smaller than the norm. I think it makes each page of posts far too long, and it isn&amp;rsquo;t immediately clear to a reader that clicking through to the individual post will render it with a larger font. As someone with fairly poor vision, this sort of thing is important to me. I could easily just change the font size on the pages showing lists of posts, but that only exacerbates how long they are. In WordPress and Hugo I&amp;rsquo;ve always used themes that show a preview of the content, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://hugo-terminal.vercel.app/&#34;&gt;Terminal&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to do something similar here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I had no idea how to achieve this, I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to since it&amp;rsquo;s something that the Carbontwelve theme does; I just needed to figure out how and copy that. After some playing around and searches to point me in the right direction of what elements may be relevant, this clever bit of CSS did the trick:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;#collection #wrapper &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;article&lt;/span&gt; {
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;max-height&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;450&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;px&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;overflow&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;hidden&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;position&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;relative&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;#collection #wrapper &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;article&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;before&lt;/span&gt;{
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    pointer-events: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;none&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;70&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;bottom&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;position&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;absolute&lt;/span&gt;;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;: linear-gradient(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;transparent&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;px&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;#282a36&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It essentially just sets a maximum height for the element showing each post, meaning that anything longer than this will be cut off. The gradient causes the post content to fade toward the same color as my background, indicating to the reader there&amp;rsquo;s more content that just isn&amp;rsquo;t visible in this particular view. Beautiful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It ended up taking me a couple of hours to get everything tweaked the way I wanted since there was a lot time spent looking things up online and even more time with trial-and-error since no one has ever accused me of being a CSS guru. I&amp;rsquo;m really happy with how it ultimately ended up, though. If anyone wants to see more of my customizations or would like to steal the theme for themselves, it&amp;rsquo;s available as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/jfabry-noc/607001f198fb5cf5a2f6551dc3b55ee5&#34;&gt;gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Office Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/home-office-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 19:06:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/home-office-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>In a move that was highly overdue, I finally redid my home office several weeks ago. It&amp;rsquo;s actually embarrassing to share, but this is what it had looked like prior to the overhaul&amp;hellip; not that I would even call this an office:
Background Saying that the desk is small is an understatement. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually owned this desk for years, and the story behind it is that I needed a small desk at my previous apartment.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;In a move that was &lt;em&gt;highly&lt;/em&gt; overdue, I finally redid my home office several weeks ago. It&amp;rsquo;s actually embarrassing to share, but this is what it had looked like prior to the overhaul&amp;hellip; not that I would even call this an office:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/old_tiny_desk.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Tiny, cramped desk with one monitor, 75% keyboard, and a laptop stand&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saying that the desk is small is an understatement. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually owned this desk for &lt;strong&gt;years&lt;/strong&gt;, and the story behind it is that I needed a small desk at my previous apartment. This was back when I was still gaming regularly (read: spending every waking moment of my life playing &lt;em&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t working.) Rather than clutter up my living room with gaming stuff, I had a decent-sized desk in my bedroom where my gaming setup lived. I started working from home 3 days a week for the job I had at the time, though, so I decided to get a second desk that I would use for that instead of trying to do both at my gaming desk, which really didn&amp;rsquo;t have the room for it considering my gaming desktop was sitting on top of it. As a result, I opted to buy this fairly small desk so that it would still fit in my bedroom alongside all the other furniture without making things feel too cramped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward several years, and I was in the middle of moving for a new job. At this point I had mostly stopped playing games, and I ended up throwing out my gaming desk since it was around 12 years old. It was fairly beat up, it had several dings along the surface that I needed to keep covered with a desk mat, and it was starting to sag in the middle. Since the job I was taking didn&amp;rsquo;t have any remote work (at the time), I decided I was okay with just moving the small desk since I&amp;rsquo;d only be using it occasionally with my personal laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a little more and the COVID19 pandemic changed everything. I started working from home full time. While using such a small desk every day felt a little silly, early on I was under the impression that we&amp;rsquo;d be going back to the office after a few weeks. It was also spring, so I tried to spend time working outside on my deck since I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going anywhere else at the time. Suffice to say, working remotely for just a few months isn&amp;rsquo;t what happened, and I became a fully remote employee. However, I just felt used to the desk and honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t give it much additional thought. This continued for several years until I eventually left that job for my current role, which is also 100% remote. At this point I realized that if I was going to keep living in my current apartment, I really needed to upgrade my setup. After some research convinced me that staying in my current home was the best decision, I knew it was time for my long-overdue upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-upgrade&#34;&gt;The Upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent some time chatting with a good friend of mine who happens to be something of a guru when it comes to all things home computing, and she helped me narrow down some of the different options that would be a good fit. I have a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; of space, as you can probably tell from the first photo, because my &amp;ldquo;home office&amp;rdquo; is actually what is intended to be my dining room. However, I have a bar-top in my apartment with several stools at it, and since I live by myself I literally always eat my meals there; I actually got rid of the table and chairs I used at my last apartment when I moved since I knew I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t use them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main idea was that I wanted to have 2 distinct setups: one for work and one for personal. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t so much for a mental break between the two but just to keep me from having to constantly be swapping peripherals between my laptops. My initial thought was to get a very long desk and have two distinct spaces right next to one another. After looking at a few options in person, though, I decided I liked the idea of two medium-length desks that I could put together in an L shape. That&amp;rsquo;s what I eventually ended up deciding to go with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/new_desk_setup_main.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;2 desks in an L configuration with 2 distinct computer setups&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way back from buying the desks, we also stopped at a computer hardware store where I bought the second (larger) monitor to include with the new setup. This allows me to just operate off of the 2 external displays while I&amp;rsquo;m working, leaving the laptop itself closed. To the right is my current personal setup, which is just a laptop on a stand that brings it close enough for me to use given how terrible my vision is. I &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; eventually get a monitor for this setup as well, but I&amp;rsquo;m also debating getting either a new laptop or swapping to a mini-PC of some sort. Until I make a firm decision on that, I&amp;rsquo;m happy enough with a laptop stand and 2 wireless peripherals I never need to worry about plugging and unplugging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also ended up changing the rest of the space a bit, taking a large chair that I had for years and tucking it into a corner after shifting around a small set of bookshelves and a replacement for the coffee table in the first photo that I swapped with a different one in my apartment to keep the all-black-everything theme going:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/new_desk_setup_lounge.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Different angle of the same office from the last photo showing the edge of the desk and a bucket chair&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes for a cozy little &amp;ldquo;lounge&amp;rdquo; part of my office. I usually sit there in the morning with a cup of coffee and read before I start work for the day. I&amp;rsquo;ll also hop into the chair to &lt;del&gt;doom&lt;/del&gt;scroll through my phone when I&amp;rsquo;m taking a break or if I&amp;rsquo;m on a call that doesn&amp;rsquo;t require me to be in front of my computer. In fact, if I&amp;rsquo;m not actively working on my computer as a part of the call, I actually like stepping away from it to ensure that I focus on the call instead of getting distracted by some code I was in the middle of working on, a Slack message, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I feel a little ridiculous for working under such cramped conditions for so long, it really was something I just got acclimated to and didn&amp;rsquo;t feel particularly inconvenienced by at the time. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded, though, this is easily my favorite part of the apartment, and I find myself spending a lot of time here even when I&amp;rsquo;m not working. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how much easier it is to focus on things like my personal side projects or maintaining this blog when I have a comfortable space to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Want Functional Scrollbars</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/functional-scrollbars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 19:02:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/functional-scrollbars/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been lamenting the death of the functional scrollbar. Remember back in the day when scrollbars looked like this?
The scrollbars were prominent because they were meant to be used. You were expected to grab one with your mouse and move it up and down. Today, scrollbars have a much different appearance and expectation of functionality. This is what they look like in Firefox on Gnome 43 running under Fedora 37:</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been lamenting the death of the functional scrollbar. Remember back in the day when scrollbars looked like this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/macos9.png&#34; alt=&#34;Folders in macOS 9 &#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scrollbars were prominent because they were meant to be &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt;. You were expected to grab one with your mouse and move it up and down. Today, scrollbars have a much different appearance and expectation of functionality. This is what they look like in Firefox on Gnome 43 running under Fedora 37:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/narrow_scrollbar_screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Super narrow scrollbar&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s just terrible. The idea here is that the scrollbar serves as more of a visual indicator of how much content is on the page rather than as something to be used directly. The problem is that I frequently find myself &lt;strong&gt;wanting&lt;/strong&gt; to use scrollbars, even in 2023. For example, as a trackball user it should be faster for me to grab a scrollbar and drag it to the top of a large body of text than it is for me to make a dozen revolutions of the scroll wheel. Trying to actually click on a bar that narrow is a challenge, though. The scrollbar will become a little wider when my mouse is over it, but 1.) not by much and 2.) it defeats the purpose if my mouse has to be over the super narrow bar in order to make it&amp;hellip; the slightest bit less narrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two terrible images I captured with my phone showcasing the problem since getting the scrollbars to even appear and then capturing a screenshot that also contains my cursor is basically impossible. I think this also does a nice job of illustrating just how narrow the default scrollbars are relative to my mouse cursor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/phone_scrollbar1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Mouse cursor next to an extremely narrow scrollbar&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once my cursor is already over it, then it looks like this&amp;hellip; which is still not good, even if it was helpful&amp;hellip; which it isn&amp;rsquo;t:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/phone_scrollbar2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Scrollbar with a cursor already over it&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox is the most egregious offender that I regularly use. For example, Gnome Terminal offers a slightly wider scrollbar that is actually possible to use. Scrollbars in GIMP are virtually akin to the macOS 9 ones and are quite nice. I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t even think about the ones in Firefox if I&amp;rsquo;m using my laptop in an undocked fashion since kinetic scrolling on the trackpad makes it trivial to quickly move between the top and bottom of a long page. When using a mouse that doesn&amp;rsquo;t also offer kinetic scrolling in the scroll wheel, though, slightly more usable scrollbars would go a long way. They don&amp;rsquo;t just have to be a visual indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying T-Mobile Home Internet</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/tmobile-home-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 18:58:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/tmobile-home-internet/</guid>
      <description>For the majority of my life, I&amp;rsquo;ve only had one Internet service provider where I lived. That was originally just a single dial-up provider when I was growing up to only having one coaxial cable provider at 4 different apartments in the span of 11 years. That recently changed when I went from having a single provider (coax) where I&amp;rsquo;m currently at to having 3 providers (coax, 5G, and fiber.)</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;For the majority of my life, I&amp;rsquo;ve only had one Internet service provider where I lived. That was originally just a single dial-up provider when I was growing up to only having one coaxial cable provider at 4 different apartments in the span of 11 years. That recently changed when I went from having a single provider (coax) where I&amp;rsquo;m currently at to having &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; providers (coax, 5G, and fiber.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the additional options on top of coax became available at the tail end of 2022, I stuck with my coax provider because I was getting a fairly steep discount from them. When that discount was about to end in February of 2023, however, I decided it was time to check out some other options. While my coax service had been (largely) reliable, the non-discounted price was a bit steep for the service offered (200 Mbps down.) This was also the same provider I had for nearly a decade in the previous town I lived in, and an absolutely terrible customer service experience with them left me with a permanent negative attitude toward them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5g&#34;&gt;5G&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first decided to try T-Mobile&amp;rsquo;s 5G home service. I use T-Mobile as my cellular provider (I think that&amp;rsquo;s a prerequisite to sign up for their home service), and in my area 5G absolutely screams, regularly pulling down 500 Mbps or more. When I came home and my phone switched from 5G to my home WiFi, it was a pretty sizable speed downgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I understand that a lot of people are still a bit leery of using a cellular network for their home Internet, I had some previous experience with this in my last job. I worked for a network company, and one of the fun toys for my home lab was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://cradlepoint.com/product/endpoints/ibr900/&#34;&gt;Cradlepoint IBR900&lt;/a&gt;. I basically double-NAT&amp;rsquo;d my home network to have all of my work-from-home gear sitting behind the Cradlepoint. In the event my terrestrial WAN link was unavailable, the Cradlepoint would fail over to AT&amp;amp;T&amp;rsquo;s LTE network (5G wasn&amp;rsquo;t really available when I got the device in 2019.) I spent a not-insignificant amount of time working from the Cradlepoint during outages, and even on LTE it was a smooth experience. As a result, I had high hopes for 5G.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I opted to try T-Mobile first is that there was really no setup involved from an installation standpoint, so if things didn&amp;rsquo;t work out it would be easy to just bail on the service. They sent me a 5G gateway the next day. All I had to do was turn it on, install their mobile app (not exactly &lt;a href=&#34;https://loopednetwork.medium.com/tp-link-ax3000-4cdb961dd761&#34;&gt;my favorite thing&lt;/a&gt;), and walk through a few steps. Since I viewed this as &amp;ldquo;kicking the tires&amp;rdquo; and still had my coax service, my plan was to simply turn off the router connected to my coax modem and make the T-Mobile SSID and PSK the same as what I was currently using so that everything I had would just automatically reconnect to the new gateway. That was a good idea, but for some absurd reason T-Mobile decided to disallow spaces in the SSID. I can&amp;rsquo;t fathom why this would be the case since having spaces in an SSID is complete valid, but there was no means by which to work around it&amp;hellip; meaning I had to reconnect all of my devices to a different wireless network to effectively test it. While that&amp;rsquo;s not a huge deal for computers, tablets, and phones, it&amp;rsquo;s truly painful for IoT devices and streaming sticks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;performance&#34;&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performance was quite good, though admittedly not as good as I was expecting. As mentioned previously, my phone (an iPhone 13) regularly pulls down 500 Mbps or more. My 5G home gateway would usually get around 200 Mbps. I could quite literally set my phone &lt;strong&gt;right&lt;/strong&gt; next to the gateway, and while on WiFi I would get 200 Mbps down while swapping my phone to 5G would result in 500 Mbps down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a speed test I had taken from my phone while connected to WiFi:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/t-mobile_wifi_speed.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;T-Mobile Home speeds&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is an example of relatively &lt;em&gt;slow&lt;/em&gt; 5G speeds on my phone itself&amp;hellip; which are still significantly better than the home service:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2023/t-mobile_5g_speed.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;T-Mobile 5G from iPhone 13&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m guessing there must be some kind of traffic shaping that&amp;rsquo;s prioritizing mobile throughput over home throughput, but that&amp;rsquo;s just wild speculation on my part. Living by myself, 200 Mbps is more than enough, though, and was comparable to my coax service that I was paying more for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been more concerned about latency and jitter, but those proved to be non-issues. Conference calls on the web, including watching screenshares and sharing my own screen, worked without any issues. RDP and SSH sessions across the Internet were similarly as performant as I would expect. Streaming video, music, and even playing online games even had no issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;problems&#34;&gt;Problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem I eventually ran into, though, was that I was struggling to maintain a consistent connection to a VPN I use to access a development environment for work. How frequently I need to be connected to this VPN varies based upon what I&amp;rsquo;m working on at any given moment, but when I need to access the VPN, I &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; to access the VPN. The behavior I saw is that it would work for some variable amount of time after connecting; sometimes it would be an hour, sometimes it would be an entire day. But occasionally it would suddenly begin to drop 50% or more of the packets, and response times would be measured in &lt;em&gt;tens of seconds&lt;/em&gt; rather than milliseconds. This would persist for anywhere from 10 minutes to an hour, at which point it would usually clear up. From there it would again continue to work for a variable amount of time before causing havoc again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the issue transpired, &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; the VPN was impacted. Connectivity to the public web was fine, as was throughput, latency, and jitter. Troubleshooting this was fairly easy since when the issue occurred, just trying to &lt;code&gt;ping&lt;/code&gt; the public-facing gateway for the VPN (not even being connected to it) would show dropped packets and latency. I saw the same behavior when I connected my laptop to my phone&amp;rsquo;s WiFi hotspot, which was naturally also using T-Mobile&amp;rsquo;s network. Then I connected to a VPS I have via SSH and attempted to &lt;code&gt;ping&lt;/code&gt; the same VPN gateway. This would show no packet loss and 40 ms response times. Likewise, Slack wasn&amp;rsquo;t blowing up with people reporting VPN issues, so clearly I was the only one experiencing a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;support&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this, I called up T-Mobile to ask them what was going on. The short of it, which I&amp;rsquo;m honestly a bit impressed that they were very upfront about, was that corporate VPNs often don&amp;rsquo;t work reliably on their network. The customer service representative I spoke to basically said there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything they could do from their end, and that if this was going to be a problem it would be best for me to use a different service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, I really appreciate the candor. On the other hand, if this is such a known issue then I think maybe some sort of disclaimer when signing up for the service would be warranted, such as noting that corporate VPNs may not be usable. If nothing else, I would&amp;rsquo;ve tested this facet much more rigorously out of the gate. Even the CSR said that when she works from home &lt;strong&gt;for T-Mobile&lt;/strong&gt; she can&amp;rsquo;t use their home Internet service due to VPN-related issues. If nothing else, she offered to make notes on my account so that if I needed to cancel after procuring another service they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t try to hassle me into staying subscribed to a service that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost as soon as that call was over I reached out to the local provider which had recently lit up fiber services in my area and got an appointment for later that week. There was already a drop in my apartment, but I would still need a strand run from that to wherever I would actually egress. Pricing was fairly aggressive, especially because&amp;ndash;as a new service in the area&amp;ndash;they were offering some special deals that I was able to take advantage of. Once the service was connected and I verified that everything worked, I called T-Mobile back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to give the original CSR credit, as when I called back and explained why I needed to cancel my service, the new CSR didn&amp;rsquo;t try to talk me into staying. She prompted processed the cancellation and provided me with a shipping label to send the 5G gateway back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the whole, I&amp;rsquo;m honestly a little bit bummed that T-Mobile&amp;rsquo;s service didn&amp;rsquo;t work out for me as I really liked the idea of it. The price was good and&amp;ndash;VPN connectivity aside&amp;ndash;the performance was great. Humorously enough, just a few weeks after I cancelled my service, I found out that my work is decommissioning the VPN I had problems with as we move our development lab to a new environment. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say T-Mobile&amp;rsquo;s service wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have the same problems with the VPN for the new environment, but it&amp;rsquo;s just amusing timing to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, I&amp;rsquo;d absolutely consider T-Mobile&amp;rsquo;s home service again if I find myself shopping around. I&amp;rsquo;d probably just try to spend some time working from my phone&amp;rsquo;s hotspot&amp;ndash;at least a few days&amp;ndash;to see if there are any obvious issues prior to opting in, though.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proton and SimpleLogin</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/proton-simplelogin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 18:57:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/proton-simplelogin/</guid>
      <description>While going down a rabbit hole on Mastodon the other day, I stumbled across a post from SimpleLogin saying that they were now a part of the Proton family. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of ProtonMail for a long time, and now also use both Proton Drive and Proton Calendar regularly (especially now that they have iOS apps.) While I&amp;rsquo;ve not used a lot of email alias services like this before, I have used the one Apple offers through iCloud.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;While going down a rabbit hole on Mastodon the other day, I stumbled across a post from &lt;a href=&#34;https://fosstodon.org/@simplelogin&#34;&gt;SimpleLogin&lt;/a&gt; saying that they &lt;a href=&#34;https://fosstodon.org/@simplelogin/110032589796645429&#34;&gt;were now a part of the Proton family&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of ProtonMail for a &lt;strong&gt;long&lt;/strong&gt; time, and now also use both Proton Drive and Proton Calendar regularly (especially now that they have iOS apps.) While I&amp;rsquo;ve not used a lot of email alias services like this before, I have used the one Apple offers through iCloud. I don&amp;rsquo;t really use my iCloud email address for anything other than apps which want to authenticate me through iCloud, which I usually accept out of convenience but opt to use a throwaway email address to avoid being spammed by them months down the line when I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped using their app. This is especially big for games that I know I&amp;rsquo;ll play for a few weeks or months and then never think about again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I happened to be feeling like blogging again&amp;ndash;hence why this site is once again live&amp;ndash;and thought I would check out a few options in the blogging space to see if I wanted to swap to something different. While trying out &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, I remembered SimpleLogin and decided to give it a shot. While it lives outside of the Proton umbrella (using it involves going to their own site rather than having it available in the Proton app switcher), I was still able to use SSO to log in via my Proton account. This also showed that I had a &amp;ldquo;Premium&amp;rdquo; account. Given that this is normally &lt;a href=&#34;https://simplelogin.io/pricing/&#34;&gt;$30 USD per year billed annually&lt;/a&gt;, I assume this must be due to my existing Proton subscription. It&amp;rsquo;s always nice to get more services and features without having to pay anything additional!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quickly generated a new alias and used that to sign up for Ghost, which worked smoothly. I get the option to either create my own alias or have an alias automatically generated via either a UUID or random words. There are additional settings for opting to suffix every alias with random numbers and which of the dozen or so domains offered by the service will be used as the default, several of which are denoted as being &amp;ldquo;premium&amp;rdquo; domains that can only be used with paid accounts. I&amp;rsquo;m curious if a service like this runs into issues where sign-ups with particular domains are blocked. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this behavior with many of the domains used by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.guerrillamail.com/&#34;&gt;Guerrilla Mail&lt;/a&gt;, for example, when I wanted to sign up for a throwaway account for something that I had zero interest in maintaining long term. I know I was concerned about the same when Apple introduced their alias service, though I figured most providers wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to turn away millions of Apple users. I&amp;rsquo;ll see over time if this becomes problematic or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with managing the aliases I&amp;rsquo;ve created, the dashboard page also provides metrics from the past 2 weeks on things like the number of messages forwarded, blocked, replied to, etc. I do find it nice that replying is an option, though I doubt it&amp;rsquo;s one that I&amp;rsquo;ll use. With my personal email account, at least, I very rarely actually &lt;strong&gt;send&lt;/strong&gt; email. In the instance that I am sending email, I want the recipient to see my actual address the overwhelming majority of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found it nice that SimpleLogin offers an iOS app that I quickly installed. At a quick glance it seems to offer essentially all of the same functionality as the web frontend.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decreasing Domains</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/decreasing-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 18:31:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/decreasing-domains/</guid>
      <description>It just dawned on me that I&amp;rsquo;ve finally made good progress in decreasing the number of domains that I own. I&amp;rsquo;ve historically purchased domains on a whim; when I&amp;rsquo;m bored or sitting on a bar stool somewhere, I&amp;rsquo;ll grab my phone and check if random domains that pop into my head are available. While the overwhelming majority of them would be taken, I&amp;rsquo;d occasionally strike upon something that hadn&amp;rsquo;t been snatched up.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;It just dawned on me that I&amp;rsquo;ve finally made good progress in decreasing the number of domains that I own. I&amp;rsquo;ve historically purchased domains on a whim; when I&amp;rsquo;m bored or sitting on a bar stool somewhere, I&amp;rsquo;ll grab my phone and check if random domains that pop into my head are available. While the overwhelming majority of them would be taken, I&amp;rsquo;d occasionally strike upon something that hadn&amp;rsquo;t been snatched up. I&amp;rsquo;d typically &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; buy them&amp;hellip; and then do nothing with them the vast majority of the time. They were basically like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icann.org/&#34;&gt;ICANN&lt;/a&gt; Pokmon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://looped.network/2022/icann_domains.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ash from Pokemon collecting domain names from ICANN&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little over a year ago, I decided that I would start to let some of my domains lapse through attrition. I turned off automatic renewal and figured that if I didn&amp;rsquo;t come up with a use for a particular domain by the time I started getting alerts about the fact that it was expiring, then I didn&amp;rsquo;t really need it in the first place. At the time I owned 9 domains. To date, I&amp;rsquo;ve let 5 of them expire. 1 was something I used for a skunk works project at my job that ended up becoming fairly critical to their workflow, so I transferred that domain to the company when I left that job. (Humorously, I never expensed this domain &amp;ndash; even after it became &amp;ldquo;production&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; because it renewed on the same date as &lt;a href=&#34;https://laifu.moe&#34;&gt;laifu.moe&lt;/a&gt;, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to submit the receipt showing both domains. ) That leaves me with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://looped.network&#34;&gt;This domain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The aforementioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://laifu.moe&#34;&gt;laifu.moe&lt;/a&gt;, the domain I&amp;rsquo;ve actually owned the longest, and the only domain I&amp;rsquo;ve ever purchased as a &amp;ldquo;joke&amp;rdquo; and actually done &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A random domain I bought prior to deciding that I&amp;rsquo;d rather just use &lt;a href=&#34;https://looped.network&#34;&gt;looped.network&lt;/a&gt; as my primary domain. I&amp;rsquo;m letting this one expire, though it has until next summer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s typically been easy for me to justify the expense of domains because I tend to use (relatively) inexpensive TLDs. I believe the most expensive domain I&amp;rsquo;ve ever purchased as a &lt;code&gt;.io&lt;/code&gt; that was around $40 USD for a year. While TLDs which are $10 to $15 a year are a bit more palatable, they still add up when I&amp;rsquo;ve got a large number of them&amp;hellip; and that cost is doing absolutely nothing if I do nothing with the domain. Today I&amp;rsquo;d only consider purchasing a domain if I have an immediate use for it; I no longer buy any just because it&amp;rsquo;s a fun name that I want to hold on to. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually had a handful of scenarios where I thought of decent domain names and discovered they were available, but so far I&amp;rsquo;ve been walking the straight and narrow without buying them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s a little silly to keep a domain for a single web page, I don&amp;rsquo;t see myself ditching &lt;a href=&#34;https://laifu.moe&#34;&gt;laifu.moe&lt;/a&gt; any time soon since my inner weeb likes it too much. &lt;a href=&#34;https://looped.network&#34;&gt;looped.network&lt;/a&gt; hosts several websites (like this one) and a few servers/services that I run, so it&amp;rsquo;s also pretty locked in. At this point I think I&amp;rsquo;d have to have something pretty outstanding that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t just host it on another subdomain of &lt;a href=&#34;https://looped.network&#34;&gt;looped.network&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Manjaro Linux Invalid Or Corrupt Package Error</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/manjaro-invalid-corrupt-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 18:30:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/manjaro-invalid-corrupt-package/</guid>
      <description>As the title alludes to, this morning I tried updating my Pinebook Pro running Manjaro Linux through my normal method:
sudo pacman -Syu Today, this resulted in an error message about the libibus package:
 warning: could not fully load metadata for package libibus-1.5.26-2 error: failed to prepare transaction (invalid or corrupted package)
 Fun. I first wanted to see if it was really just this package that was causing the problem or if there were other issues.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;As the title alludes to, this morning I tried updating my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pine64.org/pinebook-pro/&#34;&gt;Pinebook Pro&lt;/a&gt; running Manjaro Linux through my normal method:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo pacman -Syu
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, this resulted in an error message about the &lt;code&gt;libibus&lt;/code&gt; package:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;warning: could not fully load metadata for package libibus-1.5.26-2
error: failed to prepare transaction (invalid or corrupted package)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun. I first wanted to see if it was really &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; this package that was causing the problem or if there were other issues. Being a &lt;code&gt;pacman&lt;/code&gt; noob, I just used the UI to mark updates to the &lt;code&gt;libibus&lt;/code&gt; package as ignored. Once I did that, all of the other packages installed successfully. This prompted for a reboot, which I gladly did since I figured I&amp;rsquo;d see if that made any difference. Once my laptop was back up and running, though, executing &lt;code&gt;pacman -Syu&lt;/code&gt; again still gave the same error related to &lt;code&gt;libibus&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some searches online showed that a mirror with a bad package could be the problem, so I updated my mirrors via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo pacman-mirrors -f5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This didn&amp;rsquo;t solve the problem, but the new mirror gave me a different error message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;error: could not open file /var/lib/pacman/local/libibus-1.5.26-2/desc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With some more searches online, I saw a few people on the Manjaro forums say that simply creating those files was enough to fix similar errors they had with other packages. Creating the file above just resulted in an error about a second file being missing, so I ultimately ended up running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo touch /var/lib/pacman/local/libibus-1.5.26-2/desc
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo touch /var/lib/pacman/local/libibus-1.5.26-2/file
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now running an update allowed things to progress a little further, but I got a slew of errors complaining about &lt;code&gt;libibus&lt;/code&gt; header files (&lt;code&gt;.h&lt;/code&gt;) existing on the filesystem. My next less-than-well-thought-out idea was to just remove the package and try installing it fresh. I tried running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo pacman -R libibus
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, Manjaro didn&amp;rsquo;t let me do this by telling me that it was a dependency for &lt;code&gt;gnome-shell&lt;/code&gt;. Yeah, removing that would&amp;rsquo;ve been bad. It was back to searching online. The next tip I stumbled across was to try clearing the &lt;code&gt;pacman&lt;/code&gt; cache and then install updates with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo pacman -Scc
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo pacman -Syyu
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This unfortunately gave me the same error about the header files. However, the same &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.manjaro.org/t/cant-update-manjaro-invalid-or-corrupted-package/78802&#34;&gt;forum thread&lt;/a&gt; had another recommendation to run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo pacman -Syyu --overwrite &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;*&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Curious about exactly what this would do prior to running it, I checked out the &lt;code&gt;man&lt;/code&gt; page for &lt;code&gt;pacman&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bypass file conflict checks and overwrite conflicting files. If the package that is about to be installed contains files that are already installed and match glob, this option will cause all those files to be overwritten. Using &amp;ndash;overwrite will not allow overwriting a directory with a file or installing packages with conflicting files and directories. Multiple patterns can be specified by separating them with a comma. May be specified multiple times. Patterns can be negated, such that files matching them will not be overwritten, by prefixing them with an exclamation mark. Subsequent matches will override previous ones. A leading literal exclamation mark or backslash needs to be escaped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took this to mean that instead of complaining about the header files that already existed on the filesystem, it would simply overwrite them since my glob was just &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; to match &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt;. I ran this, and sure enough everything was fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mainly run Manjaro on my Pinebook Pro just because it&amp;rsquo;s such a first class citizen there with tons of support. It&amp;rsquo;s now the default when new Pinebook devices ship; back when I got mine it was still coming with Debian, though I quickly moved it over after seeing how in love the community was with Manjaro. I do find that I run into more random issues like this on Manjaro than I do with Fedora on my other laptop or Debian on my servers, for example, and at times it can be a little frustrating. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to spend a chunk of my Saturday morning troubleshooting this, for example. But while there seem to be more issues with Manjaro, the documentation and community are so good that usually after a little time digging in, the solution can always be found. I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to run into any issue where the &lt;a href=&#34;https://loopednetwork.medium.com/pop-os-upgrade-issues-e8bc95935ff8&#34;&gt;current installation was a lost cause&lt;/a&gt; forcing me to reinstall the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting Audio From Video With FFmpeg</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/ffmpeg-audio-from-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 18:28:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/ffmpeg-audio-from-video/</guid>
      <description>Just a few moments ago I needed to extract the audio component out of a video file into some type of standalone audio file, like .mp3. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Audacity to record audio, I figured maybe it had some capability for ripping it out of video.
My initial searches gave me results like this which quickly made it clear that while this is technically possible, it requires some add-ins that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to mess around with.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Just a few moments ago I needed to extract the audio component out of a video file into some type of standalone audio file, like &lt;code&gt;.mp3&lt;/code&gt;. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.audacityteam.org/&#34;&gt;Audacity&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;em&gt;record&lt;/em&gt; audio, I figured maybe it had some capability for ripping it out of video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My initial searches gave me results like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SP8IONsqMVk&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; which quickly made it clear that while this is technically possible, it requires some add-ins that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to mess around with. However, since the add-in mentioned in that video was for &lt;a href=&#34;https://ffmpeg.org/&#34;&gt;FFmpeg&lt;/a&gt;, I realized I could just use that directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have &lt;code&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/code&gt; installed, but that was easy enough to rectify on Fedora 36.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo dnf install ffmpeg-free
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then I needed to extract the audio. I first checked how it was encoded in the video with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;ffprobe my_video.mp4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After sifting through the output, I saw that it was encoded as &lt;strong&gt;aac&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stream #0:1&lt;a href=&#34;eng&#34;&gt;0x2&lt;/a&gt;: Audio: aac (mp4a / 0x6134706D), 48000 Hz, stereo, s16, 317 kb/s (default)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than that, I wanted to simultaneously re-encode the audio as MP3. Another quick search showed me some &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/9913032/how-can-i-extract-audio-from-video-with-ffmpeg&#34;&gt;great resources&lt;/a&gt;. Ultimately, I ended up doing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;ffmpeg -i my_video.mp4 -q:a &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; -map a bourbon.mp3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/a/36324719&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow post&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;code&gt;-q:a 0&lt;/code&gt; parameter allows for a variable bitrate while while &lt;code&gt;-map a&lt;/code&gt; says to ignore everything else except the audio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a few moments later, and my MP3 was successfully encoded.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kubectl logs Symbolic Link Error</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/kubectl-symbolic-link-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 18:27:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/kubectl-symbolic-link-error/</guid>
      <description>I recently ran across an interesting error with my development Kubernetes cluster, and while I still have no idea what I may have done to cause it, I at least figured out how to rectify it. As is commonly the case, most of the things I end up deploying to Kubernetes simply log to standard out so that I can view logs with the kubectl logs command. While running this against a particular deployment, though, I received an error:</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I recently ran across an interesting error with my development Kubernetes cluster, and while I still have no idea what I may have done to cause it, I at least figured out how to rectify it. As is commonly the case, most of the things I end up deploying to Kubernetes simply log to standard out so that I can view logs with the &lt;code&gt;kubectl logs&lt;/code&gt; command. While running this against a particular deployment, though, I received an error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;failed to try resolving symlinks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the details of the error message, it seemed that running a command like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;kubectl logs -f -n &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;namespace&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;podname&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is looking for a symbolic link at the following path:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/var/log/pods/{namespace}_{pod-uuid}/{namespace}&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end file itself seems to be something extremely simple, like a number followed by a &lt;code&gt;.log&lt;/code&gt; suffix. In my case, it was &lt;strong&gt;4.log&lt;/strong&gt;. That symbolic link &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; points to a file at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/var/lib/docker/containers/{uuid}/{uuid}-json.log&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where the &lt;strong&gt;uuid&lt;/strong&gt; is the UUID of the container in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The directory above isnt even viewable without being root, so depending on your setup you may need to use &lt;code&gt;sudo ls&lt;/code&gt; to be able to look at whats there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to open the &lt;strong&gt;-json.log&lt;/strong&gt; file and validate that it had the information I needed, so I just had to create the missing symlink. I did that with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo ln -s /var/lib/docker/containers/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;uuid&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;uuid&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;-json.log 4.log
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since my shell was already in the &lt;strong&gt;/var/log/pods/{namespace}_{pod-uuid}/{namespace}&lt;/strong&gt; directory, I didnt need to give the full path to the actual link location, just specify the relative file of &lt;strong&gt;4.log&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, after creating this I was able to successfully run &lt;code&gt;kubectl logs&lt;/code&gt; against the previously broken pod.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kinit Fails Only When Using Keytab File</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/kinit-keytab-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 18:26:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/kinit-keytab-fail/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been working through getting WinRM connectivity working between a Linux container and a bunch of Windows servers. I&amp;rsquo;m using the venerable pywinrm library. It works great, but there was a decent bit of setup for the underlying host to make it work that I had been unfamiliar with; you can&amp;rsquo;t just create a client object, plug in some credentials, and go. A big part of this for my setup was configuring krb5 to be able to speak to Active Directory appropriately.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been working through getting WinRM connectivity working between a Linux container and a bunch of Windows servers. I&amp;rsquo;m using the venerable &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/pywinrm/&#34;&gt;pywinrm library&lt;/a&gt;. It works &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt;, but there was a decent bit of setup for the underlying host to make it work that I had been unfamiliar with; you can&amp;rsquo;t just create a client object, plug in some credentials, and go. A big part of this for my setup was configuring &lt;a href=&#34;https://pkgs.alpinelinux.org/package/edge/main/aarch64/krb5&#34;&gt;krb5&lt;/a&gt; to be able to speak to Active Directory appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My setup involves a container that runs an SSH server which another, external service actually SSHs into in order to execute various pieces of code. So my idea was to take the entrypoint script that configures the SSH server and have it also both:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a keytab file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use it to get a TGT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a &lt;code&gt;cron&lt;/code&gt; job to keep it refreshed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s pretend the AD account I had been given to use was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Username@sub.domain.com&#34;&gt;Username@sub.domain.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my manual testing, this worked fine after I was prompted for the password:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;kinit Username@SUB.DOMAIN.COM
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re completely new to this, note that it&amp;rsquo;s actually critical that the domain (more appropriately called the &amp;ldquo;realm&amp;rdquo; in this case) is in all capital letters. If I run this manually by &lt;code&gt;exec&lt;/code&gt;ing my way into a container, I get a TGT just like I&amp;rsquo;d expect. I can view it via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;klist -e
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, things didn&amp;rsquo;t go smoothly when I tried to use a keytab file. I created one in my entrypoint shell script via a function that runs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    echo &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;addent -password -p Username@SUB.DOMAIN.COM -k 1 -e aes256-cts-hmac-sha1-96&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    sleep &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    echo &amp;lt;password&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    sleep &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    echo &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;wkt /file.keytab&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; | ktutil &amp;amp;&amp;gt; /dev/null
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The keytab file is created successfully, but as soon as I try to leverage it with&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;kinit Username@SUB.DOMAIN.COM -kt /file.keytab
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;I receive a Kerberos preauthentication error. After much confusion and searching around online, I finally found an &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.cloudera.com/t5/Community-Articles/quot-kinit-Preauthentication-failed-while-getting-initial/ta-p/346998&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; that got me on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article discusses the fact that an assumption is being made under the hood that the salt being used to encrypt the contents of the keytab file is the realm concatenated together with the user&amp;rsquo;s samAccountName (aka &amp;ldquo;shortname&amp;rdquo;). So for my sample account, the salt value would be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SUB.DOMAIN.COMUsername&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem highlighted by the article is that when you authenticate via the UserPrincipalName format (e.g.: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:username@domain.com&#34;&gt;username@domain.com&lt;/a&gt;) rather than the shortname format (e.g.: domain\username), another assumption is made that the prefix of the UPN is the same as the shortname. This is very commonly not the case; in a previous life where I actually was the AD sysadmin, I had shortnames of first initial and last name while the UPNs were actually firstname dot lastname. So for example, my UPN was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:looped.network@domain.com&#34;&gt;looped.network@domain.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While my samAccountName was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lnetwork&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this type of mismatch happens, you can use &lt;code&gt;-s&lt;/code&gt; when running &lt;code&gt;addent&lt;/code&gt; to specify the salt. After checking AD, I verified in my current case that the username was the same for both properties&amp;hellip; but that in both places it was completely &lt;em&gt;lowercase&lt;/em&gt;. I can&amp;rsquo;t say why it was given to me with the first character capitalized, but after re-trying with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:username@SUB.DOMAIN.COM&#34;&gt;username@SUB.DOMAIN.COM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, everything was successful. This made sense to me because while AD doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about the username&amp;rsquo;s capitalization when it authenticates (hence why manually running &lt;code&gt;kinit&lt;/code&gt; and typing the password worked), using a keytab file means that the wrong salt was given.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Time Error Checking and Code Completion With Neovim</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/neovim-lsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 18:25:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/neovim-lsp/</guid>
      <description>I had written a few months ago on Medium that I was trying to switch from using VS Code as my main editor to Vim. As I mentioned in that post, I&amp;rsquo;ve used Vim for years now, but never as my &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; editor for when I need to get serious work done, such as with my job. I also swapped from vanilla Vim to Neovim, which I found to have a few quality of life improvements that I enjoyed.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I had written a few months ago on &lt;a href=&#34;https://loopednetwork.medium.com/state-of-vim-2022-6ad0a6722a7a&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; that I was trying to switch from using &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt; as my main editor to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vim.org/&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt;. As I mentioned in that post, I&amp;rsquo;ve used Vim for &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt; now, but never as my &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; editor for when I need to get serious work done, such as with my job. I also swapped from vanilla Vim to &lt;a href=&#34;https://neovim.io/&#34;&gt;Neovim&lt;/a&gt;, which I found to have a few quality of life improvements that I enjoyed. I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t stick with it, though, because I missed the how frequently VS Code saved me from myself when I did things like making stupid mistakes that I&amp;rsquo;ve need to debug manually because my editor wasn&amp;rsquo;t telling me about the problems in advance. Likewise, I got irritated when I kept having to check things like what parameters I needed to pass to a method or where I defined a particular class manually because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t easily peek them like I can in VS Code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, I knew this functionality was possible in Neovim (and Vim), but I just never bothered to check exactly how. During some initial homework on the matter, it seemed like parts of it were fairly simple while other parts were complicated. Ultimately, it turned out that how difficult the process is to set everything up really depends on how difficult you want to make it and how much you want to customize things. I just reproduced the steps I originally followed on my work laptop with my personal laptop to validate my notes prior to making this post, and it probably took me less than 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plugins-and-initvim&#34;&gt;Plugins and &lt;code&gt;init.vim&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started with Neovim, I quite literally told it to just use what I had already set up with Vim as far as configuration and plugins were concerned. I had used &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen&#34;&gt;Pathogen&lt;/a&gt; for my Vim plugins and had my configuration done in &lt;code&gt;~/.vimrc&lt;/code&gt;. Neovim looks for configuration files in &lt;code&gt;~/.config/nvim&lt;/code&gt;, and they can be written in Vimscript, Lua, or a combination of the two. I initially just had my &lt;code&gt;init.vim&lt;/code&gt; file with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-vimscript&#34; data-lang=&#34;vimscript&#34;&gt;set runtimepath^=~/.vim runtimepath+=~/.vim/after
let &amp;amp;packpath = &amp;amp;runtimepath
source ~/.vimrc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was taken straight from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://neovim.io/doc/user/nvim.html#nvim-from-vim&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;. It worked fine, but I wanted to keep my configs separate in this case. I started my just copying the content of my existing &lt;code&gt;.vimrc&lt;/code&gt; file to &lt;code&gt;~/.config/nvim/init.vim&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; If you&amp;rsquo;re curious, my full Neovim configuration is on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/-/snippets/2391236&#34;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I wanted a plugin manager. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/junegunn/vim-plug&#34;&gt;vim-plug&lt;/a&gt; seems to be extremely popular and was simple enough to install with the command they provide:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sh -c &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;curl -fLo &amp;#34;${XDG_DATA_HOME:-$HOME/.local/share}&amp;#34;/nvim/site/autoload/plug.vim --create-dirs \
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;       https://raw.githubusercontent.com/junegunn/vim-plug/master/plug.vim&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then I just updated my &lt;code&gt;init.vim&lt;/code&gt; with the plugins I wanted to install:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-vimscript&#34; data-lang=&#34;vimscript&#34;&gt;call plug#begin(&amp;#39;~/.config/plugged&amp;#39;)
Plug &amp;#39;https://github.com/joshdick/onedark.vim.git&amp;#39;
Plug &amp;#39;https://github.com/vim-airline/vim-airline.git&amp;#39;
Plug &amp;#39;https://github.com/tpope/vim-fugitive.git&amp;#39;
Plug &amp;#39;https://github.com/PProvost/vim-ps1.git&amp;#39;
Plug &amp;#39;https://github.com/wakatime/vim-wakatime.git&amp;#39;
Plug &amp;#39;neovim/nvim-lspconfig&amp;#39;
Plug &amp;#39;neoclide/coc.nvim&amp;#39;, {&amp;#39;branch&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;release&amp;#39;}
call plug#end()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;call plug#begin(&#39;~/.config/plugged&#39;)&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;call plug#end()&lt;/code&gt; indicate what configuration pertains to vim-plug. The path inside of &lt;code&gt;call plug#begin&lt;/code&gt; is where plugins get installed to; I could pick whatever arbitrary location I wanted. Plugins can be installed with any valid git link. You can see above that there&amp;rsquo;s a mix of full URLs and a shorthand method. I started off by just copying the links for plugins I already used with Vim (all of the full GitHub links) and then adding the others as I looked up how to do some additional configuration. More on those later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;code&gt;init.vim&lt;/code&gt; updated, I just needed to close and re-open Neovim for everything to apply, followed by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;:PlugInstall
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This opens a new pane and shows the progress as the indicated plugins are all installed. What&amp;rsquo;s really cool about this is that I can also use &lt;code&gt;:PlugUpdate&lt;/code&gt; to update my plugins, rather than going to my plugin folder and using &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; commands to check for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;note-on-configuration&#34;&gt;Note On Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ultimately ended up doing all of my configuration in Vimscript. I would actually prefer to use Lua, but most of the examples I found were using Vimscript. I also have a fairly lengthy function in my original Vim configuration for adding numbers to my tabs that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have to rewrite, especially since I wholesale copied it from somewhere online. Depending on what you want to do, however, you may end up with a mix of both, especially if you find some examples in Vimscript and some in Lua. This is entirely possible. Just note there can be only &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;init&lt;/code&gt; file, either &lt;code&gt;init.vim&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;init.lua&lt;/code&gt;. If you create both, which is what I initially did, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a warning each time you open Neovim and only one of them will be loaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use &lt;code&gt;init.vim&lt;/code&gt; as a base and then also import some Lua configuration(s), I created a folder for Lua at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;~/.config/nvim/lua&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In there, I created a file called &lt;code&gt;basic.lua&lt;/code&gt; where I had some configuration. Then, back in &lt;code&gt;init.vim&lt;/code&gt;, I just added the following line to tell it to check this file as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-vimscript&#34; data-lang=&#34;vimscript&#34;&gt;lua require(&amp;#39;basic&amp;#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;error-checking&#34;&gt;Error Checking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; I ended up not using the steps below, so if you want to follow along with exactly what I ended up using, there&amp;rsquo;s no need to actually do any of the steps in this section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where some options come in to play. Astute readers may have noticed the second to last plugin in my vim-plug config was for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Plug &amp;#39;neovim/nvim-lspconfig&amp;#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is for the LSP, or Language Server Protocol. This allows Neovim to talk to various language servers and implement whatever functionality they offer. However, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually come with any language servers included, so I needed to get those and configure them as needed. For example, I could install &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/neovim/nvim-lspconfig/blob/master/doc/server_configurations.md#pyright&#34;&gt;pyright&lt;/a&gt; from some other source, like NPM:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;npm i -g pyright
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then I needed additional configuration to tell Neovim about this LSP. The samples were in Lua, which is why I initially needed to use Lua configuration alongside Vimscript:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lua&#34; data-lang=&#34;lua&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;require&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;lspconfig&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;.pyright.setup{}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This actually worked for me with respect to error checking. Opening up a Python file would give me warnings and errors on the fly. However, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get any code completion. I started looking at options for this, but frankly a lot of them seemed pretty involved to set up, and I wanted something relatively simple rather than having to take significant amounts of time configuring my editor any time I use a new machine or want to try out a different language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-completion&#34;&gt;Code Completion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I stumbled onto onto &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/neoclide/coc.nvim&#34;&gt;Conquer of Completion&lt;/a&gt;, or coc. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why it took me so long to find as it seems to be &lt;em&gt;insanely&lt;/em&gt; popular, but better later than never. One of coc&amp;rsquo;s goals is to be as easy to use as doing the same thing in VS Code, and I honestly think they&amp;rsquo;ve nailed it. I first installed it via vim-plug in &lt;code&gt;init.vim&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Plug &amp;#39;neoclide/coc.nvim&amp;#39;, {&amp;#39;branch&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;release&amp;#39;}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;After restarting Neovim and running &lt;code&gt;:PlugInstall&lt;/code&gt;, I could now install language servers straight from Neovim by running &lt;code&gt;:CocInstall&lt;/code&gt; commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;:CocInstall coc-json coc-css coc-html coc-htmldjango coc-pyright
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;After this, I fired up a Python file and saw that I had both error checking &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; code completion. There was just one final step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-mapping&#34;&gt;Key Mapping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the wide array of key mapping options and customizations that people do, coc doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to make any assumptions about what key mappings are available and which may already be in use. As a result, there are NO custom mappings by default. Instead, they need to be added to your Neovim configuration just like any other mapping changes. However, the project shares a terrific example configuration with some recommended mappings in their &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/neoclide/coc.nvim&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;. I legitimately just copied the sample into my existing &lt;code&gt;init.vim&lt;/code&gt; file. This adds some extremely useful mappings like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gd&lt;/code&gt; to take me to the declaration for what I&amp;rsquo;m hovering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;K&lt;/code&gt; to show the documentation for what I&amp;rsquo;m hovering (based on the docstring for Python, for example.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;]g&lt;/code&gt; to go to the next error/warning and &lt;code&gt;[g&lt;/code&gt; to go to the previous one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Tab&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Shift + Tab&lt;/code&gt; to move through the options in the code completion floating window.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt; to select the first item in the code completion floating window.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A function to remap &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + f&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + b&lt;/code&gt;, which are normally page down and page up, to scroll up and down in floating windows but only if one is present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And tons of other stuff great stuff. I initially spent about 30 minutes just playing around with some throwaway code to test all of the different options and key mappings. It honestly feels super natural and now gives me the same benefits of VS Code while allowing me to use a much leaner and more productive editor in Neovim.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling GSS-NTLMSSP For Alpine Linux</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/gss-ntlmssp-alpine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 18:23:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/gss-ntlmssp-alpine/</guid>
      <description>I recently found myself working on a project which required the GSS-NTLMSSP library. The application is going to be delivered via Kubernetes, so I needed to build a Docker image with this library. The project&amp;rsquo;s build instructions are pretty clear about what the dependencies are, but given that this was going to be a Docker image, I wanted to use Alpine Linux as the base image in order to keep the image size as small as possible.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I recently found myself working on a project which required the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gssapi/gss-ntlmssp&#34;&gt;GSS-NTLMSSP&lt;/a&gt; library. The application is going to be delivered via Kubernetes, so I needed to build a Docker image with this library. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gssapi/gss-ntlmssp/blob/main/BUILD.txt&#34;&gt;project&amp;rsquo;s build instructions&lt;/a&gt; are pretty clear about what the dependencies are, but given that this was going to be a Docker image, I wanted to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alpinelinux.org/&#34;&gt;Alpine Linux&lt;/a&gt; as the base image in order to keep the image size as small as possible. The problem with this is that Alpine is just different enough to require different dependencies, publish their &lt;a href=&#34;https://pkgs.alpinelinux.org/packages&#34;&gt;packages&lt;/a&gt; under different names, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started off by just doing things manually where I fired up a local Docker container running the base &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/_/alpine&#34;&gt;Docker image&lt;/a&gt; and then manually installing each package via &lt;code&gt;apk add {package_name}&lt;/code&gt; to make troubleshooting easier. Once I had all of the packages from the aforementioned build documentation, I ran &lt;code&gt;./configure&lt;/code&gt;, looked at the errors, figured out which package was missing, installed it, and tried again. After several iterations of this process, &lt;code&gt;./configure&lt;/code&gt; executed successfully and it was time to attempt running &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; ran for a minute but then would error out with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;undefined reference to &amp;rsquo;libintl_dgettext&#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seemed odd to me because while running &lt;code&gt;./configure&lt;/code&gt; I had received an error that &lt;code&gt;msgfmt&lt;/code&gt; couldn&amp;rsquo;t be found, and I had installed &lt;code&gt;gettext-dev&lt;/code&gt; in order to accommodate that. After some additional packages searches, I discovered the &lt;code&gt;musl-libintl&lt;/code&gt; library is also available. I attempted to install &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; but received an error that it was attempting to modify a file controlled by the &lt;code&gt;gettext-dev&lt;/code&gt; package. I uninstalled that via &lt;code&gt;apk del gettext-dev&lt;/code&gt; and then ran into another error that&amp;ndash;duh&amp;ndash;&lt;code&gt;msgfmt&lt;/code&gt; was now missing again. I handled that by just installing the vanilla &lt;code&gt;gettext&lt;/code&gt; package, not the &lt;code&gt;-dev&lt;/code&gt; version, and then &lt;strong&gt;finally&lt;/strong&gt; everything compiled successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is the full list of packages that I needed in order to get the build to succeed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;autoconf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;automake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build-base&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;docbook-xsl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doxygen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;findutils&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gettext&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;krb5-dev&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libwbclient&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libtool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libxml2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libxslt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libunistring-dev&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;m4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;musl-libintl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pkgconfig&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;openssl-dev&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;samba-dev&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zlib-dev&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; is included just to clone the repo, and &lt;code&gt;build-base&lt;/code&gt; is the meta package I used for compiling C software since just installing something like &lt;code&gt;gcc&lt;/code&gt; will not include everything needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing Functions, Classes, and Methods From Other PowerShell Files</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/powershell-import-classes-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 18:20:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/powershell-import-classes-functions/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been working on a project that requires me to use PowerShell. I actually feel relatively fluent in PowerShell since it was my main scripting language for a little over a decade while I worked as a sysadmin in highly Windows-centric environments that involved me automating as much of my job as possible in order to be able to do things like sleep on occasion. However, my PowerShell work rarely (read: never) went beyond single file scripts.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been working on a project that requires me to use PowerShell. I actually feel relatively fluent in PowerShell since it was my main scripting language for a little over a decade while I worked as a sysadmin in highly Windows-centric environments that involved me automating as much of my job as possible in order to be able to do things like sleep on occasion. However, my PowerShell work rarely (read: never) went beyond single file scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this project being a decent bit more complicated and with the potential for some of the code to be useful in future projects, I wanted to figure out how to actually break things up into useful chunks, just like I would do when writing something in Python. Fortunately, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t terribly difficult to figure out, though, as is typically the case with PowerShell, the documentation was a bit wanting. I had to put information together from a few different resource and go through a little trial-and-error to actually figure it out since Microsoft can never just seem to give clear, concise examples of anything PowerShell-related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I needed to realize is that I wanted to create my files not with a normal &lt;code&gt;.ps1&lt;/code&gt; extension but with a &lt;code&gt;.psm1&lt;/code&gt; extension to indicate that they were PowerShell modules. Only the file that would normally be executed directly has a &lt;code&gt;.ps1&lt;/code&gt; extension. I kind of hate this since it makes things more difficult to test individually; in Python, for example, I could just create a main function that executes when:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; __name__ &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;__main__&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then I can add things in &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; while building it out that are later ignored when the code is called from elsewhere. PowerShell doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer anything like this, though it&amp;rsquo;s not a huge ordeal. After creating a &lt;code&gt;.psm1&lt;/code&gt; file, it can contain functions, classes, and/or methods. For example, here&amp;rsquo;s a sample file called &lt;code&gt;helloFunc.psm1&lt;/code&gt; with just a function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34; data-lang=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; Write-Hello {
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;param&lt;/span&gt;(
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;        [&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;Parameter&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;Mandatory&lt;/span&gt;=$true)]&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;[string]&lt;/span&gt;$Name
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    )
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    Write-Output &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Hello, $Name.&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s a file called &lt;code&gt;personClass.psm1&lt;/code&gt; with both a class and a couple of methods:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34; data-lang=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;class Person {
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;[String]&lt;/span&gt;$Name
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;[int]&lt;/span&gt;$Age
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# Constructor.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    Person(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;[String]&lt;/span&gt;$Name, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;[int]&lt;/span&gt;$Age) {
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;        $this.Name = $Name
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;        $this.Age = $Age
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;[String]&lt;/span&gt;GreetPerson(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;[String]&lt;/span&gt;$PreferredGreeting) {
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;($PreferredGreeting &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-eq&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-or&lt;/span&gt; $null &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-eq&lt;/span&gt; $PreferredGreeting) {
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;            $PreferredGreeting = &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Hello&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;        }
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;$PreferredGreeting, &lt;/span&gt;$($this.Name)&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;. I can&amp;#39;t believe you&amp;#39;re &lt;/span&gt;$($this.Age)&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt; years old.&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;[void]&lt;/span&gt;HaveBirthday() {
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;        $this.Age++
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neither file has an entrypoint, though that&amp;rsquo;s expected since they&amp;rsquo;re designed to be called from somewhere else. Here&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;code&gt;main.ps1&lt;/code&gt; file which ties them all together:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34; data-lang=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;#!/usr/bin/env pwsh&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;using module ./personClass.psm1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;using module ./helloFunc.psm1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Write-Hello -Name &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Garrett&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$me = &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;[Person]&lt;/span&gt;::new(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Garrett&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, 9000)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Write-Output $me.GreetPerson(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Salutations&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$me.HaveBirthday()
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Write-Output $me.GreetPerson(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Salutations&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most important thing here are the two &lt;code&gt;using&lt;/code&gt; statements, which specify that I&amp;rsquo;m going to import the two aforementioned files. Once I do this, I can then call classes, methods, and functions in those files directly.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Cloud Variables Are All Strings</title>
      <link>https://looped.network/posts/terraform-cloud-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 18:19:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://looped.network/posts/terraform-cloud-variables/</guid>
      <description>This post easily falls into the so ridiculous that it shouldnt be a post category. However, considering how long I ended up stuck on it earlier today, I figure its worth making if it stands a chance of helping even one other person avoid the same fate as me. 
Ive started doing a little bit of work with the Terraform Cloud API. Specifically, I was looking at being able to update a workspace variable through code.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This post easily falls into the so ridiculous that it shouldnt be a post category. However, considering how long I ended up stuck on it earlier today, I figure its worth making if it stands a chance of helping even one other person avoid the same fate as me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ive started doing a little bit of work with the Terraform Cloud API. Specifically, I was looking at being able to update a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.terraform.io/cloud-docs/api-docs/workspace-variables&#34;&gt;workspace variable&lt;/a&gt; through code. In this case, I was trying to change a variable I called &lt;code&gt;replica_count&lt;/code&gt; which, if the name wasnt enough of a giveaway, I was using to track how many replicas should be used in a Kubernetes container spec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found that I was able to easily get back all of my workspace variables via a &lt;code&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://app.terraform.io/api/v2/workspaces/{workspace_id}/vars/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, trying to make a &lt;code&gt;PATCH&lt;/code&gt; to&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://app.terraform.io/api/v2/workspaces/{workspace_id}/vars/{variable_id}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; with a body in JSON to specify the change resulted in a 500 internal server error response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JSON in the body wasnt very complex. I only needed to modify the value. As the documentation specifies, and the &lt;code&gt;type&lt;/code&gt; must be set to vars and the &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; must be set to the ID of the variable to change. This is a bit odd to me since I &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; have to give the ID in the URL, but its not a big deal. The &lt;code&gt;attributes&lt;/code&gt; property then can optionally contain whatever property or properties need to be updated. In my case, the JSON just looked like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    data: {
        id: var_id,
        type: vars,
        attributes: {
            value: 2
        }
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;There isnt a lot to go wrong here&amp;hellip; but I managed to do it! I finally figured out what was wrong when I changed my &lt;code&gt;PATCH&lt;/code&gt; to a &lt;code&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; just to validate that my JSON had to be the culprit. The &lt;code&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; responds with JSON which is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; similar to what I needed to send, and thats what tipped me off to the fact that the value of the variable is &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; a string, even if Im thinking of it as a number in my head. So my &lt;code&gt;value&lt;/code&gt; line needed to be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;value: 2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;After seeing that in the response to my &lt;code&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt;, I updated my JSON, re-&lt;code&gt;PATCH&lt;/code&gt;ed, and saw that everything was successful.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
